

Andres Guzman Cordero

ABOUT ME

Highly organized and detail-oriented honours student studying how economics and mathematics help us understand and model human behaviour. My interests are broad, including the study of dynamical systems, machine learning, experimental economics and the implementation of research tools. I enjoy generating new ideas and devising feasible solutions to broadly relevant problem. My colleagues would describe me as a driven, resourceful individual who maintains a positive, proactive attitude when faced with adversity.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish -C2
- English -C2
- Dutch B1
- German A2

CONTACT



Amsterdam, Netherlands

+31 (0) 6 14 34 42 90

andres@andresguzco.com

www.linkedin.com/in/andresguzco

www.andresguzco.com

EDUCATION

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

2020 - 2023 | BSc. in Economics and Econometrics

- Honours Programme student.
- Education Committee Member.
- Covered courses Economics and Mathematics total of 264 ECTS.

Universidad Autonoma de San Luis Potosi

2016 - 2019 | BSc. in Medicine, BSc. in Surgery, MBBS. (Not Concluded)

 Award for Medical Case exposition during 10th National Congress of the UASLP Faculty of Medicine.

Stanford University

2022 | Machine Learning Certification

• Introduction to modern machine learning, including supervised learning (logistic regression, neural networks, etc) and unsupervised learning (clustering, dimensionality reduction, recommender systems).

EXPERIENCE

2022 -2023 ING

Global Sector Research Intern

• Provide direct support to senior Credit research & strategy colleagues with the aim to constantly improve the product range, investor presentations, and run quantitative tasks.

2022 **Bit**

Student Researcher

 As part of the team, we continuously tried and prototyped the newest technologies out there. In my projects, I worked with deep neural networks, NLP and speech recognition.

2022 - 2023 Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Research Assistant

• Research on projects such as Applied Spatial General Equilibrium Models. Wrote a paper on the analysis of commuting dynamics in The Netherlands.

2017 - 2019 Laboratorio de Genómica Viral UASLP

Research Assistant

 Developing and applying DNA-based methods for use in molecular epidemiology and genetic characterisation of viral infectious diseases (HIV, Influenza and Hepatitis B)

PROJECTS

- Project 1: Abstract and the techniques used.
- Project 2: Abstract and the techniques used.
- Project 3: Abstract and the techniques used.
- **Project 4**: Abstract and the techniques used.
- Project 5: Abstract and the techniques used.

SKILLS

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Machine Learning (TensowFlow, Scikit-Learn) Volunteer's Coordinator | "Nicolas Aguilar" Nursing
- Statistical Programming (R, Stata, EViews)
- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, etc)
- SQL
- Git
- VBA

- Volunteer's Coordinator | "Nicolas Aguilar" Nursing
 Home | 2014-2015
- Medical Volunteer | San Pablo Foundation for Children with Cancer | 2017-2018
- Vice President, Faculty Chapter, International Federation of Medical Student Associations | 2018-2019



Andres Guzman Cordero

ABOUT ME

Highly organized and detail-oriented honours student studying how economics and mathematics help us understand and model human behaviour. My interests are broad, including the study of dynamical systems, machine learning, experimental economics and the implementation of research tools. I enjoy generating new ideas and devising feasible solutions to broadly relevant problem. My colleagues would describe me as a driven, resourceful individual who maintains a positive, proactive attitude when faced with adversity.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish -C2
- English -C2
- Dutch B1
- German A2

CONTACT



Amsterdam, Netherlands

+31 (0) 6 14 34 42 90

□ andres@andresguzco.com



in www.linkedin.com/in/andresguzco

www.andresguzco.com

EDUCATION

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

2020 - 2023 | BSc. in Economics and Econometrics

- Honours Programme student.
- Education Committee Member.
- Covered courses Economics and Mathematics total of 264 ECTS.

Universidad Autonoma de San Luis Potosi

2016 - 2019 | BSc. in Medicine, BSc. in Surgery, MBBS. (Not Concluded)

• Award for Medical Case exposition during 10th National Congress of the UASLP Faculty of Medicine.

Stanford University

2022 | Machine Learning Certification

• Introduction to modern machine learning, including supervised learning (logistic regression, neural networks, etc) and unsupervised learning (clustering, dimensionality reduction, recommender systems).

EXPERIENCE

2022 - 2023 ING

Global Sector Research Intern

 Provide direct support to senior Credit research & strategy colleagues with the aim to constantly improve the product range, investor presentations, and run quantitative tasks.

2022 Bit

Student Researcher

• As part of the team, we continuously tried and prototyped the newest technologies out there. In my projects, I worked with deep neural networks, NLP and speech recognition.

2022 - 2023 Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Research Assistant

• Research on projects such as Applied Spatial General Equilibrium Models. Wrote a paper on the analysis of commuting dynamics in The Netherlands.

2017 - 2019 Laboratorio de Genómica Viral UASLP

Research Assistant

• Developing and applying DNA-based methods for use in molecular epidemiology and genetic characterisation of viral infectious diseases (HIV, Influenza and Hepatitis B)

PROJECTS

- Project 1: Abstract and the techniques used.
- **Project 2**: Abstract and the techniques used.
- Project 3: Abstract and the techniques used.
- **Project 4**: Abstract and the techniques used.
- Project 5: Abstract and the techniques used.

SKILLS

VOLUNTEER WORK

- Statistical Programming (R, Stata, EViews)
- Python (Numpy, Pandas, Seaborn, etc)
- SQL
- Git
- VBA
- Machine Learning (TensowFlow, Scikit-Learn) Volunteer's Coordinator | "Nicolas Aguilar" Nursing Home | 2014-2015
 - Medical Volunteer | San Pablo Foundation for Children with Cancer | 2017-2018
 - Vice President, Faculty Chapter, International Federation of Medical Student Associations | 2018-2019